Guide to the Armand Weiss Washington Academy of Sciences and George Washington University related materials collection, 1968-1992 MS2317
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Armand Weiss Washington Academy of Sciences and George Washington University related materials collection
1968-1992
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Weiss, Armand B.
MS2317
1.5 Linear Feet 3 document boxes
Armand Weiss is a alumnus of the George Washington University who served as president of the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1990-1991. This collection contains administrative files from the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1983 to 1992, as well as materials from the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Doctoral Association, the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Alumni Association, and the George Washington University General Alumni Association.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains administrative files from the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1983 to 1992, as well as materials from the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Doctoral Association, the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Alumni Association, and the George Washington University General Alumni Association.
Biographical / Historical
Armand Weiss is a alumnus of the George Washington University who served as president of the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1990-1991. He received a BS and MBA from the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania, and a Doctor of Business Administration from the George Washington University in 1971. He began his career in the Navy, as Assistant to the Auditor General, then served as project director at the Center for Naval Analyses and the Logistics Management Institute. He then began a career in the federal government, first as the Director of Systems Integration and Coordinator of Project Independence at the Federal Energy Administration in 1973, and as the first Coordinator of the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve. He then worked as Senior Economist of the National Commission on Supplies and Shortages in 1976. After his federal career, Weiss founded Associations International, Inc., a nonprofit management company. In addition to his work with the Washington Academy of Sciences, he has been very active in alumni associations, Democratic political activities, philanthropic organizations, and operations research organizations.
Other Finding Aids
Please see RG0026 Office of Alumni Relations Records, Series 5: http://library.gwu.edu/ead/rg0026.xml#ref347 and Series 15: http://library.gwu.edu/ead/rg0026.xml#ref1354 for more information on the George Washington University General Alumni Association.
Arrangement
Collection: Organized into two series: Washington Academy of Sciences, and George Washington University alumni materials
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Armand Weiss, 2013 (2013.017)
Weiss, Armand B.
- Washington Academy of Sciences, 1983-1992; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains administrative files from the Washington Academy of Sciences from 1983 to 1992, including financial information, membership, correspondence, bylaws, and minutes.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Washington Academy of Sciences 990s, 1985-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences Board, 1988-1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences Bylaws, 1989; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences Disputes/Contracts, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences financial, 1983-1989; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences Journal, 1990-1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences letters, 1985-1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences membership, 1988-1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences membership, 1988-1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences minutes, 1985-1991; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences press, 1990-1991; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences reactions and meetings, 1986-1990; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Washington Academy of Sciences Vice President -- Admin, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- George Washington University alumni materials, 1968-1989; Series 2
  This series contains administrative files kept by Armand Weiss including the constitutions, bylaws, minutes, and correspondence of the following alumni organizations from 1968 through 1989: the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Doctoral Association, the George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Alumni Association, and the George Washington University School General Alumni Association.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Doctoral Association, 1968-1971; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University School of Government and Business Administration Alumni Association, 1972-1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University School General Alumni Association, 1974-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)